Next, we are going to make the fold at the waist.
If the fold we want now is horizontal,
it means that the vertical fold is longer than the original length,
so we can make the fold at the waist.
So we need to extend the length of the side.
The direction of the extension is to drag along the original direction with the Ctrl key.
In the process of dragging, remember to press the Ctrl key,
do not put the right key in the process of dragging,
you can enter the specific number.
I have stretched 40 mm here, which is about 4 cm.
After the front is adjusted,
the back is also extended by entering the same number in the same way.
After extension, press the control key to simulate briefly.
Now we can see that its length is stretched.
Then we can drag the side panel in the state of opening simulation.
Because the waist is tight now,
we can stack the panels near the waist.
In order to better observe the fold effect of the waist,
we can first reduce the particle diameter of the panel to 5,
and then simulate.
When the particle diameter becomes small,
the grid will be re-placed once.
At this time, if you start the simulation,
or say that we have some changes to the panel,
then these folds may disappear.
So we find the fabric here,
in the property editor,
increase the friction coefficient of the fabric.
In this way, the friction between the fabric and the fabric,
including the friction between the fabric and the virtual model,
will become larger.
Then the folds that we drag out manually will not disappear easily.
If we drag out more at a time,
there may be more folds.
So as long as we drag the panel in the opposite direction,
we can pull the fold a little bit.
Here, you can try to get used to this feeling.
Then you can adjust it according to the need through friction.
In addition to the length of our side,
the position of this cutting line in the middle
can also be slightly stretched down a little bit.
In this way, there will be more fabric
that can be piled on the waist here.
Because we have changed the grid again,
it will have some re-training,
then we will manually adjust its position.
In addition,
if we need to make this fold look more obvious,
more hard,
then we can increase the resistance of the fabric to the waist,
and also increase the rigidity of the fabric to the foot line.
In this way, the stretch performance of the fabric in three directions will become worse.
When the stretch performance becomes worse,
the fold will be more obvious.
Then we can follow the effect we want
to manually drag the position of the fold.
If we want the fold to dissipate in a certain place,
we can pull it in the opposite direction.
You can practice this feeling more.
Then we are going to make the hemline.
Making the hemline is very simple.
After selecting the center line,
press the Shift key to select more lines.
When selecting more lines,
pay attention to select the middle section as well.
After selecting all the lines,
right-click to select the inner line.
Then enter the value of the inner line.
Pay attention to the value of the input when creating the inner line.
Do not let the inner line exceed the line.
Otherwise, the inner line will not be cut.
Now, because we cut off the edge,
the fixing pin has been deleted.
Then we create the fixing pin again.
Press the W key,
the left mouse button,
click on the panel,
then select these two fixing pins.
To select more,
press the Shift key,
you can select more.
To select more,
use these two fixing pins,
then right-click,
select the fixing pin,
and fix it on the virtual model.
Then we will see that
the fabric near the fixing pin may be stretched.
Then we drag it by hand.
Do not let the fixing pin look too bumpy.
In addition,
we can hit a few more fixing pins.
It is also possible to fix it on the chest of the virtual model.
The cutting line of many rabbit women's clothes
is very obvious.
Then we can use the edge line tool
to select these sewing lines.
Press the Shift key,
you can select more.
After selecting these sewing lines,
we can set the folding angle of the sewing line
in the property editor.
When the folding angle is greater than 180 degrees,
it will bend the sewing line
along the sewing line,
so that the effect of the sewing line
will be more obvious.
If in the simulation process,
we find that there are a lot of fish
at the bottom of the chest,
or press Alt 4,
we will see that
there are some extra spaces in the middle,
we can use the edge line tool
to select a small section of the curve line
on the side of this curve line,
move it a little bit to the middle,
and then adjust its point.
What we do is to reduce its fabric,
make it tighter.
But because it involves the change of the grid again,
then the effect of our previous adjustment
may have some changes,
so we may manually adjust its position.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to contact us.
Thank you.
We want to transition from this position
to the next position.
This is mainly because
we are using the reverse fold method,
so now the fold effect
is more satisfactory.
Or afterwards,
I don't want to cause its fold
to disperse due to dragging,
then we can select these several versions,
right-click and select shape alter.
After shaping,
the fold effect will be more obvious,
so you have to pay attention.
If you think this effect is too obvious,
we can now use the edge sewing line tool
so that the folding effect will be a little weaker.
If you reduce it too much, you can just raise it a little bit.
On the other hand, don't forget to format.
After formatting the template, it will maintain these folds.
And if we turn on the simulation, it will also interact with the action.
But these folds will not be modified because of our action adjustment.
Thank you for watching.